Shubham Vyas

+91 9589417383 | hxyro0@gmail.com | Github | Linkedin

SUMMARY

experienced in Linux Administration, Configuration Management, Continuous Integration, Continuous Deployment, Release Management, database management, and Cloud Implementations. also familiar with EC2, S3, ELB, EKS, RDS, Cloud watch, SNS, Elastic IP's, and managing security groups, IAM on AWS. experienced in automating, configuring, and deploying instances on AWS, and Administration of various environments in the software development life cycle.

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Information Technology (IIIT) Bhopal

Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology

Bhopal, MP Expected 2024

(Software Engineering, Computer Networks, DBMS, Operating Systems, Data Structure, and Algorithms)

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer - www.makerble.com

Makerble.com, Remote

August 2022 – Present

- Completed the Migration of Production and the rest of the environments from Heroku to AWS while automating infrastructure provisioning with 100% Terraform coverage in aws.
- Responsible for Continuous Integration (CI) and Continuous Delivery (CD) process implementation using argord and tekton along with Python and Shell scripts to automate routine jobs.
- Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using Argocd and tekton, Actively manage, improve, and monitor cloud infrastructure on AWS, EC2, S3, and RDS, including backups, patches, and scaling
- Reduced costs by ~74% by eliminating unnecessary servers, consolidating databases, and utilizing spot instances
- Supported the infrastructure of makerble, including AWS EC2 instances, RDS databases, Elastic Load Balancers, S3 buckets, Cloudflare DNS records, and Cloudfront CDN distribution.
- Deployed Self-hosted variants of Saas (like Openreplay, Metabase), Provided Oncall support for production issues and developer assistance.
- Worked with Docker for a convenient environment setup for development and testing.
- designed infrastructure and developed utilization reports, presenting to 8 stakeholders and 2 senior managers

Full Stack Developer Intern - www.metastart.in

Metastart.in, Remote

July 2022 – August 2022

- Implemented authentication and authorization for admin-panel dashboard via firebase, implemented Inventory UI from scratch for team liquid plus website keeping UX in mind
- Wrote Docker files for NodeJs applications

PROJECTS

CICD Pipelines

October 2022

Implemented deployment pipelines to deploy the Ruby On Rails applications along with data pipelines for backing up databases, synchronizing production databases with other environments, and cleaning up unused EBS volumes.

Documentation and inbuilt maintenance mechanism.

Modifier - Next-Gen URL Modifier

May 2022

https://github.com/hxyro/modifier

The project contains Kubernetes manifest files, helm charts for deployment on any cluster like EKS, terraform files for setting up Jenkins on AWS-EC2, Optimized and secure docker and docker-compose files, AWS code pipeline for continuous integration, and Github actions for code linting.

ANFT - Web2 image auctioning website

June 2022

https://github.com/hxyro/ANFT

A Full-stack web application for Image auctioning.

Implemented web Image crop functionality with react-easy-crop

Enabled user to upload Images directly to AWS s3 bucket via s3 temporary URL

Terra-Vpn - Personal VPN On AWS-Cloud

August 2022

https://github.com/hxyro/terra-vpn

Used Terraform to set up and launch AWS-EC2 instance for OpenVPN server with custom VPC, subnet, route-table, internet-gateway, security_group, and Elastic IP

Rcli - Command-line Image Browser for Reddit

December 2021

https://github.com/hxyro/rcli

A Bash script to scrape data from Reddit-API

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

GNU / LINUX Users Club

Club Secretary

2021 – Present

- Encouraging students to use Linux, Open Source, and DevOps
- Organized events with 100+ participants

Kratigence Club

Webmaster

2021 - 2022

- Conducting webinars related to Statistics behind machine learning algorithms
- Promoting the culture of Data Science with our discord server being active 24*7

SKILLS

Linux: Arch Linux, Ubuntu, Alpine, NixOS

Kubernetes: Operator Pattern, Helm Configuration, Sidecar Pattern, Service mesh **Ci/Cd:** ArgoCD, Argo Workflows, Tekton, Github Actions, Gitlab CI, Jenkins **Programming Languages:** JavaScript, Python, Bash Scripting, Rust, Solidity, C

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres, Redis

DevOps Stack: Linux, AWS, Nginx, Docker, Terraform, Grafana, Prometheus **Soft Skills**: Public Speaking, Leadership, Communication Skills, Management Skills